Sybil is a drama, tv movie film directed by Joseph Sargent.
A true story of a young woman whose abusive childhood results in
her developing a multiple personality disorder.
Dr. Cornelia Wilbur, played by Jessica Lange.
Sybil Dorset, played by Tammy Blanchard.
Hattie Dorsett, played by JoBeth Williams.
Young Sybil, played by Alison Murray.
Ramon, played by Fab Filippo.
Willard, played by Brian Downey.
Sybil is a 2007 American made-for-television drama film directed by Joseph Sargent, and written by John Pielmeier, based on the 1973 book Sybil by Flora Rheta Schreiber, which fictionalized the
story of Shirley Ardell Mason, who was diagnosed with multiple personality disorder (more commonly known then as "split personality", now called dissociative identity disorder).
This is the second adaptation of the book, following the Emmy
Award-winning 1976 mini-series Sybil that was broadcast by NBC.
The university scenes were filmed at Dalhousie University in Nova Scotia.
In January 2006, The Hollywood Reporter announced CBS had greenlit
the project, but it was shelved after completion.
The film was released in Italy, New Zealand, the Dominican Republic, Brazil, Norway and
Hungary before finally being broadcast in the US by CBS on June 7, 2008.
The tone is emotional.